08/16/2014

Wanling Zhang
Program Manager, Adult Language & Studio Programs
China Institute

Dear Mr./Ms. Zhang,

It is my pleasure writing to you for applying Mandarin adult teacher/tutor position in your organization.

I have strong experience in language teaching and training programs. I had been teaching English in Beijing Medical University for special training program to senior doctors both in oral and reading classes for two years. While working in the US Embassy in Beijing, I was a tutor in learning Chinese program in the Embassy. I also worked with Global Education Foundation for eight years in Washington DC on special training programs. Although those training program were not focus on language, I had great knowledge in teaching skills.

I have very strong experience in communication and inter-personal skills. During the working time within MCI and Asia Pacific Capital, I have handled almost all the inter-personal issues smoothly and gained great relationship within the firms, as well as business partners.

I am a native mandarin speaking person and speaking English for over 30 years. I firmly believe that I am qualified for Mandarin language teacher and tutor position and I will bring extra benefit to your organization through my hard and enthusiastic work, as I love teaching and dealing with people.

I appreciate your consideration on my application. Should you have any questions or need any further reference, please let me know through my contact information in my resume.

I am looking forward to hearing from you soon.

Kind personal regards,

Michael Wang

Michael Wang

20 Newport Parkway Jersey City, NJ 07310 646-342-1688

Michael.y.wang@hotmail.com

Summery:

Over 35 year management and teaching experience in Diplomatic Affairs, Specialized Training, Business operation management in Financial security market fields. Fully understanding both social and business environments of United States and China.

Education:

1980 – 1982 Beijing Second Foreign Language College

English Literature Major

1989 – 1992 The George Washington University

International Finance Management (MBA)

Working Experience:

1979 – 1986 Supervisor, US Embassy in Beijing China

Duties:

Managed administrative work force to provide service and support to American
Diplomats in Beijing. Maintain relationship with Chinese Governments to ensure the
services level in personnel, logistic services, Utilities providing services and public
security areas.

1986 – 1989 Office Director, United Nations Development Program In Beijing, China Duties:

- Managed Accounting, Travel, Administrative and Customs Offices to provide service and support to UNDP Financial Aid programs in China.
- Monitoring Funds using progress to meet UNDP funding requirement.

1987- 1989 English teacher, Beijing Medical University in Beijing, China (Part Time)

Duties:

Teaching Doctor Training program in English oral and reading classes.

1992 - 1996 Supervisor, Manager, Leading Manager MCI Telecommunication International Service Center in Washington DC Member of establish team to build MCI multi-language service center Duties:

> Managed seven languages teams to provide quality services 7/24 to MCI in-language customers.

1996 - 2004 Founder of Dapol International, Inc. in Washington DC

VP of Global Education Foundation

Established Dapol International and cooperated with GEF (one of the seventeen institutes in the States authorized by China Foreign Experts Bureau) to provide customized training

program for Chinese central, provincial and local officials, as well as entrepreneurs of Chinese business enterprises in the United States.

Specialized training programs include both short term (15 days) and Mid-term (30-90 days):

- 1. Urban and Rural Development program
- 2. Logistic design and management program
- 3. American Education System program
- 4. American Security Law and Financial Market Management System program
- 5. Small Business in USA program Etc.

2004 – 2013 CEO, Asia Pacific Capital, Inc. in New York (APC) www.nyapc.net Duties:

- Managed a PE funds, Invest into Chinese Pre-IPO firms in the States
- Providing financial consulting services to Chinese Pre-IPO companies through entire public process in the States.

CEO, Regal Financial Information Co. Ltd in Beijing, China Subsidiary company of Asia Pacific Capital, Inc.

A Strategy partner firm with Shenzhen Stock Market, providing service of:

- China Public Companies financial data;
- Public companies activities monitoring system;
- Trading Platform for public investors;
- Financial Information of Chinese Public Companies in US Security Markets.

Language skills: affluent in both Mandarin and English.